但是不肯给我
but she wouldn't let me keep them.
好吧
All right.
我要知道这个人是谁
I want to know who this guy is.
他说他叫苏林斯
Said his name was Sullins.
阿历克斯感谢你过来
Alex, thanks for coming in.
你好兰
Hello, Lang.
怎么回事? 有许多警察
What's going on? There's all kinds
在搜查你的办公室
of suits over here going through your office.
我认识你是吗
I know you, huh?
恐怕认错了
Afraid not.
不 没有
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
你是麦克法登
You're McFadden.
你把我和别人搞混了
You've confused me with someone else.
应该是在大使那儿
You were with the ambassador.
你不了解我 我也不了解你
You don't know me, I don't know you,
不过你的任务是把我弄出去
but it's your job to get me out of here.
-你们明天就越狱 -下午三点
You break out tomorrow. By 3:00 p.m.
-你是说凌晨吧 -不 是下午
You mean a.m. No, I mean p.m.
我们明天就动手 就在大白天
We're doing this tomorrow in the middle of the day.
把戒指给我
Give me the ring.
算你聪明
Wise decision.
戒指要吗 兄弟?
Want the rin brother?
这可不是我的作风 伙计
That's more your style, man.
没关系 没关系的
It's all right, it's all right.
你们都退开 退开
You all go on back. Go ahead.
别 快退开
No, go ahead.
小意思
A word.
你以后要更小心一点
You should try and be more careful in the future.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
你叫什么?
What's your name?
帝格
Tyge.
迈克
Michael.
那个澳洲人
The Australian.
你说你是在尼斯认识他的
You said you knew him from Nice.
是真的吗
Is that true?
你在说我是个骗子?
You calling me a liar now?
他说你满口谎话
He says you're full of it.
他说他从没做一个大使
He said he was never an ambassador.
不 不是一个大使
No, not an ambassador,
我说"大使"
The Ambassador.
我曾在大使宾馆的服务台工作
I was concierge at the Ambassador Hotel.
我可以发誓 他曾在那干过几个月
I could've sworn he worked there for a few months.
谁知道呢 对吗
Who the hell knows, huh?
我经常磕药
I was high half the time.
这也是我被炒的原因
Kind of why I got fired.
是我在这儿的原因
Kind of why I'm in here.
他在尼斯做什么?
What was he up to in Nice?
怎么?
What?
你要出书吗
You writing a book?
我们3点13走 还有三小时又
We're leaving at 3:13 that gives us three hours
41分钟 但我们还没办法进禁入区
41 minutes. And we still don't have a way into no-man's-land.
我会搞定的
l'll take care of that.
-只是我得先查探一下 -那监狱围栏呢?
I just need to check it out first. And the fence?
你那个掘墓人朋友只洒过一次药水
Your grave digger friends only sprayed the thing once,
我可不希望今天我被上电刑
And I'd just assume not get electrocuted today.
苏克雷多洒一次会让我更有安心点吗 是的
Would I feel better if Sucre had sprayed the fence again? Yes.
这可能吗 不
Is that an option? No.
除非他又有进来的理由
Unless he had another reason to be there.
你要做什么?
What are you going to do?
杀个人好让他进来洒药水?
Kill someone to get more spray on the fence?
我倒想杀了你 如果这能帮我们逃出去的话
I'd think about killing you if it helped us get out of here today.
知道什么能帮我们逃出去吗
You know what'll help us get out of here?
一把梯子
A ladder.
迈克
Michael
我们逃出去后要去哪儿?
where are we gonna go once we get through that fence?
去弄把梯子来
Just get me a ladder.
这张吊床比以前那个短
This hammock's shorter than the last one.
那我们得弄点别的东西来接长它
Well, we might need something to extend it.
好了 我来想办法
All right, I'll take care of it.
我从没去过尼斯
I've never been to Nice.
听说那儿很美
I hear it's beautiful.
我怎么知道
I wouldn't know.
我不管这个人是不是认识你
I don't care if this guy knows you or not.
我在意的是
But what I do care about is
他很明显一直在盯着你
his apparent fixation with watching you at all times.
斯科菲尔德有访客
Scofield. Get a visita.
我们很快就会出去了
We'll be out of here soon enough.
他不是问题
He won't be a problem.
斯科菲尔德有访客
Scofield, you have a visitor.
伙计 看看这个
Hey, buddy, check it out.
你们国家有玩骰子吗
Do they roll bones in your country?
到我房间来 我教你
Come to my cell, I'll teach you.
你要我去你牢房玩骰子?
You want me to come back to your cell and"roll bones"?
真友好啊
Real subtle.
很好玩的
Hardy har-har.
是啊是啊 很有趣
Yeah, yeah, yeah, it's hilarious.
告诉我
Tell me,
你对这里所有没衣服穿的人都这么友好吗
are you this friendly with all the shirtless guys in Sona?
我昨天给了你吃的
I gave you food yesterday.
我给了你睡觉的地方
I gave you a place to sleep.
我很好奇原因
I wonder why.
你该死的有什么毛病?
What the hell is your problem?
听着 我不想和你上床 明白吗
Look, I just don't want to have sex with you, okay?
这很难接受吗
Is that so hard to believe?
拿个盘子
Get a plate.
要穿过禁入区
To make it across no-man's-land,
我们必须对付两名守卫
we're going to have to disable two of the tower guards.
一个已经可以搞定了
I've already taken care of one of them.
另一个需要你的帮助
With the other one, we're going to need your help.
每天中午1点到2点
Every day between 1:00 and 2:00,
是他的午休时间
he takes his lunch break.
他会喝一杯咖啡
He gets a cup of coffee.
你得找出放杯子的地方 下点药进去
You need to find out where and put something in that cup.
确保我们越狱时他意识不清
Make sure he's unconscious during the escape.
你让我在三个小时之内把这事搞定?
You're dropping this on me with three hours to go?
-我不知道该说什么 -3点13?
I don't know what to tell you. 3:13?
3点13开始动手
3:13 is when it starts.
我们3点25抵达海滩
We'll be on the beach by 3:25.
在大白天
In broad daylight.
组织仍以为我们是在今晚9点
The Company still thinks we're doing this at 9:00
开始行动 对吗
tonight, right?
听着 我不能再骗这些人了迈克
Listen, I can't lie to these people anymore, Michael.
我们需要时间查看人质移交点
We need time to survey the transfer site,
看看有没有办法把莎拉和LJ救出来
to figure out if we can get LJ and Sara out of there
以防他们玩阴的
in case they try something.
-你弄到枪了? -是的 我弄到了
You got the gun? Yeah, I got the gun.
LJ怎么样? 莎拉呢?
How's LJ? How's Sara?
他们没事
They're fine.
照片呢?
What about the pictures?
我拿不到照片
I can't get pictures.
我要照片 林肯
I need them, Linc.
我拿不到照片
I can't get the pictures.
我们怎么肯定他们还活着?
How do we know they're still alive?
他们是我愿做这事的唯一原因啊
They're the only reason I'm doing this.
苏珊说他们很好
Susan says they're fine.
-相信她吧 -你总是告诉我
Just trust her. You're the one who's always telling me
不能相信任何人
we can't trust anybody.
现在你 你却为这个人做担保?
Now you're you're vouching for this person?
没时间了
There isn't enough time.
听着 如果我在今天中午2:30之前
Listen, if I don't see pictures of LJ and Sara by 2:30
看不到LJ和莎拉的照片
this afternoon,
我哪里都不会去
I'm not going anywhere.
YYeTs人人影视字幕组出品
最新最快字幕下载请登录：www.YYeTs.net
■
字幕：YYeTs人人影视字幕组  后期：梁良
我找不到美国产的奶酪
Can't seem to find American cheese down here.
希望你喜欢阿萨德产的
I hope you like Asadero.
没事 很好
Yeah. It's perfect.
几年前 我在摩苏尔打仗
A couple of years ago, I was serving in Mosul.
我被敌人俘虏了
And I was taken prisoner.
过了几个漫长的晚上后
A few nights later,
我听到了美军直升机的声音
I could hear the sound of U.S. Army helicopters.
越来越近
Two clicks and closing.
我的手当时是被绑着的
My hands were still tied behind my back,
但我还是逃了
and I I ran.
我当时没有想到
It didn't occur to me
如果这是一次营救任务
that if this was a rescue mission,
那么敌人也会听到直升机声音的
my captors could hear the choppers.
我没有想到
It didn't occur to me
这次的任务其实是人质交换
that this was actually a hostage exchange,
但是
and that
我的逃跑会被视为
jumping would be viewed
敌对行为
as a hostile act.
我很快又被抓起来了
I got recaptured immediately.
6名突击队员死于
Six Rangers died
枪战
in the firefight.
接下来的三个星期
And for the next three weeks
这么说吧
Let's just say
人都是畜牲
men are pigs.
我们丑话说在前头
Let's be clear.
这是一次交换
This is an exchange.
不要逞能
If you don't try to be a hero,
这样你和你爸爸都不会有事
you and your father will be okay.
-明白了吗? -明白
Okay? Okay.
很好
Good.
吃吧
Eat.
诺曼? 诺曼?
Norman? Norman?
你该知道
As you can imagine,
他喜欢勒齐
he prefers Lechero.
诺曼?
Norman?
他不管你交不交保护费都会杀了你
He kills you before or after he does your taxes.
他杀你可不需要理由
He Kills you when he pleases.
我口渴了
I'm feeling thirsty.
你为什么不帮我们拿点喝的 小子
Why don't you go fix us something to drink, boy?
也许你还没接到通知
Maybe you ain't got the memorandum,
我已经被提升了
but I've been promoted.
小子
Boy.
你刚才对我说什么?
What did you say to me?
有什么事吗
What's the problem?
有人打肿脸充胖子
Stumpy herand his mouth.
就是这个问题
That's the problem.
我现在就要和他出去把问题解决
I'm calling him out right now
我会和他谈谈 你出去
I'll talk to him. Leave.
这事没完
This isn't over.
都出去
Leave
我们只是
We was just, uh
不 不
No, no, no.
你欠我个情
The favor you owe me
你发现了什么吗
What have you found out?
这种事情是要时间的
A thing like this takes time.
我不可能走到他面前直接问
I can't just walk up to them and say,"Hey, whoever's been
谁背叛了勒齐请举手
betraying Lechero, raise your hand."You know?
我让你在这里当我的耳线
I asked you to be my ears in this prison,
你什么料都收不到?
and you hear nothing?
我只知道每一次我坐下来准备
All I know is every time I try and sit down and begin
了解点什么的时候 萨米总是扯开话题
sussing things out, Sammy always changes the subject.
我不是说他就是叛徒 但
Not that I'm saying he's the guy, but
我不想听你的理论
I don't want to hear your theories.
我要的是结论
I want results.
情况还好吗
Is everything okay?
-詹姆斯怎么样? -是的 他很好
Is James all right? Yeah, he's fine.
这东西哪里来的?
Where is this from?
乌瑞伯 在波德格的
Uribe's, the roadside
路边 就几公里远
Bodega a few kilometers away.
如果我想你去辩认一个警卫
If I needed you to ID a specific guard
哨塔的警卫 你能做得到吗?
a tower guard could you do it?
我只是不想被抓起来
I just don't want to get busted.
到底能不能做到?
Could you do it or not?
可以
Yes.
-林肯? -是的
Lincoln? Yeah.
-什么事? -我需要点帮助
What is it? I need something.
蒂博格也干不了什么坏事的 老兄
Teodoro's harmless, man.
-他是一个 小丑 -一个该死的小丑
He's a he's clown. He's a dead clown.
老兄 我不会到处说
Hey, man, I wasn't going to say anything,
但是 昨晚
but, uh, last night,
我在找扑克的时候 你猜怎么着
I was looking for my playing cards and guess what?
我发现了这个
I found these.
你竟然瞒着我
You're holding out on me.
喜欢都拿去
Take'em.
口感很差
They taste nasty.
老兄 你找不到再好的雪茄了
Man, you cannot get a better cigar than this.
你从谁那里拿的? 奥古斯特?
Where'd you get these? Augusto?
他要给我 我也阻止不了
I can't make him stop sending them in to me,
不过我可不是他的人 你明白吗?
but I don't work for him, you understand?
你确定不介意?
You sure you don't mind?
我在这附近
I was in the neighborhood.
我那么老远过来探望我?
You came all this way to visit?
我来是想把你弄出来
I came to get you out of here.
我能在48小时之后把你转去Schaum
I can have you in Schaum Correctional Facility
的监禁中心
in 48 hours.
在圣路易斯
In St. Louis.
苏林斯希望把你关在相对戒备森严的地方
Sullins wanted a medium security,
但我说服了他
but, uh, talked him down.
他给我什么的方案作为交易?
What sort of deal is he getting me?
25年?
25 years?
终身监禁?
Life?
上级给予我们很大的让步
The director's giving us a lot of latitude
以此交换你在政府对林肯·布鲁斯
in exchange for testimony against the government
这次阴谋事件上的证词
in the Lincoln Burrows conspiracy.
那么
So
8年怎么样?
how does eight years sound?
苏林斯安排好
Soon as Sullins finishes up,
我们准备好车
we can have a van ready
我不接受
I don't think so.
什么?
What?
谢谢你们的努力
I appreciate the effort,
你的努力 但是 我不能忍受被关押8年
your effort, but, um, I can't do eight years.
你现在最起码要坐10年
You're doing ten now.
政府现在需要你做点事
The government is calling in some favors.
一旦你回到美国 如果你不合作
Once you're in the U.S., if you don't cooperate,
他们会起诉你所有的犯罪行为
they're going to charge you with everything.
那可包括多起谋杀案的
That's multiple homicide counts.
你不答应这交易
Without this deal,
你一辈子都要在牢里了
you are gonna be in prison for the rest of your life.
谢谢你们的努力
I appreciate the effort,
你的努力
your effort.
但我不能
But I can't.
阿历克斯
Alex.
我们行动的时候 如果
While we're getting out of here, and
如果我不能成功
if I don't make it,
你能答应我一定将这个给我女朋友吗
will you make sure this gets to my girlfriend?
好的
All right.
你知道的 如果你 我也可以帮你这么做
You know, uh I could do the same for you.
把这个绑紧了
Tie an anchor bend there.
我只是提一下
I was just offering.
你知道吗 如果我逃不出去
You know what, if I'm the one who doesn't make it,
如果你真心想帮我
and you really want to do me a favor,
就是坚持与对方的谈判
just hold up your end of the bargain.
我会尽我所能的
I'll do everything I can.
我希望那是真的
I hope that's true.
那个结是从哪来的?
How's that knot coming?
你看
There.
我合格了吗?
Did I pass your test?
我告诉过你我是个渔民
I told you I'm a fisherman.
进展如何?
Where are we?
我发现了一个能让我们到达禁入区的牢房
I found a cell that'll get us into no-man's-land.
比从我的旧牢房到达围墙要远一些
It's a longer run to the fence than my old one,
但必须得从那走
but it's gonna have to do.
哪一间? 谁住那?
Which one? Who liveshere?
帕波乔还有萨米
Papo, Cheo and Sammy.
听着 我知道你在想什么
Look, I know what you're thinking,
但这是第二层唯一另一间
but it's the only other cell on the second floor
可以不被岗哨发现直达围墙的牢房
with a direct line to the fence, where we won't be seen
我们怎么保证
the other tower guards. And how do we
他们不会在那出现?
guarantee that they won't be there?
到两点时 每个人都会到操场
By 2:00, everyone should be out in the courtyard
观看午餐足球比赛
for the lunchtime soccer game.
你确信那还没开始?
You sure it hasn't started already?
某人不经过决斗来解决问题
Someone went outside the ring to settle a dispute.
现在 谁破坏了这个规矩
Now, anyone who affronts our justice system
谁就要被依此受惩罚
in this way must be punished.
现在 我知道那懦夫不敢吭声
Now, I know the coward won't come forward.
但如果有人有关于此事的信息
But if anyone has information about this shameful act,
告诉我
I demand to know.
-走吧 穆多 -干吗?
Let's go, Menudo. Why?
勒齐想找你 快走
Lechero wants you. Move your ass.
每天我看你在院子里呆着
Now, every day I see you out in the yard,
玩你的美国运动
you play your American sports
穿着你的美国球衣
and wear your American clothes.
我觉得从你来之后
I don't think I've heard you
没你说过一句西班牙语
speak one word of Spanish since you've been here.
我想练习英文
I like to practice my English.
没什么不好
And why shouldn't you?
美国是个伟大的国家
America is a great nation.
"一个不可分割的国家 自由与公正属于所有人"
"One nation, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all."
没错吧?
Is that right?
对
Yes.
没错
对所有人都要公平
Justice for all.
你我都一样
Justice for you and justice for me.
而对
And justice for
那个在院子里杀了布朗齐多的凶手也要公平
whoever killed that blanquito in the yard.
我知道你为什么在那一言不发
Now, I know why you didn't say anything out there.
但你每天都在那玩恶心的美国游戏
But you play your silly American games all day long,
就在尸体被发现的楼梯前面
right in front of the stairs where the body was found.
现在 如果你不告诉我你看到了什么
Now, if you don't tell me what you saw,
会有你好看的
there will be consequences.
我 我看到一个人走进楼梯间
Well, I-I saw one person go into the stairwell.
好像一分钟之后 我听到争吵声
A-And then maybe a minute later, I heard an argument.
你看到谁了?
Who did you see?
那么在我们松开绳子后
So after we tie the cord off
我们切断栏杆 打通窗户
we dig out the bar, we pop open the grate,
然后我们就逃出去 没错吧迈克?
and we're, and we're down, right, Michael?
有人想说说
Does anyone want to say anything
我们刚看到的东西吗?
about what we just saw out there?
说什么?
What is there to say?
首先 一小时前
Well, for starters, an hour ago,
你说也许我们得杀个人
you say maybe we should kill someone
然后就有人被杀了
and then someone gets killed.
我没说过 而那
I didn't say that, and this is exactly
就是我们现在必须关注的
what we should be focusing on right now.
让我们花几个小时
Let's spend a couple of hours worrying
担心在这鬼地方的另一具尸体
about another dead body in this hellhole.
你们要干吗?
What do you want?
What are you doing?
勒齐想见你
Lechero wants to see you.
我什么信息都没有
I don't have any information.
他不需要信息
He doesn't want information.
他需要招供
He wants a confession.
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything.
他说的没错 他是无辜的
Listen to him; he's innocent.
那你想招供?
You want to confess?
那你来代替他啊
You can easily switch places.
也许现在我们得开始担心
Maybe now we should start worrying
那个真正的杀手了吧?
about who the real killer is, huh?
是啊 但在这里
Yeah, but in this place,
也许有一百个人在嫌疑名单上
there could be a hundred people on that list.
除了我觉得在死者脖子底部
Except I'm thinking a single stab wound
有个刀疤 而那伤口一看就是高手干的 阿历克斯
to the base of the neck looks pretty professional, Alex.
我当时正有人探视 老兄
I was in visitation, Kojak.
什么让你这么肯定惠斯勒没杀人?
And what makes you so sure that Whistler didn't do it?
他可是与他有纠葛的人
He's the one that had the run-in with the guy.
不可能 他不会为这事去冒险
No, he's got too much to lose.
惠斯勒出局了 即使不是现在
Whistler's gone, and if not now,
也快了 所以就剩我们俩
he probably will be soon, so it's you and me.
没有所谓的我们俩
There's no you and me.
我们不会丢下他逃走的
We're not leaving here without him.
在两个小时内 我将要爬出窗户 翻过那围墙
In two hours, I'm going out that window and through that fence.
是吗? 很好
Oh, yeah? Yeah, that's right.
你想跑哪去 阿历克斯?
And where are you going to go to, Alex?
哪都去不了
Anywhere but here.
只有一条路能出去
There's only one road out,
树林里有24小时不间断巡逻
and the jungle is under constant patrol by police 24-7,
那我再问一次 你想跑哪去阿历克斯?
so, again, where are you going to go to, Alex?
3点13分 我会离开的
3:13, I'm gone.
我说过我对此一无所知
I told you I know nothing about this.
我不应该
I shouldn't
我不该被带这来
I shouldn't be here.
我能向你保证 我没杀人
I can promise you I, I did not kill that man.
有人看到你走下楼梯
Someone saw you go down the staircase.
楼梯 还有什么证据吗?
Stai.. is there any other proof?
我的人会找到证据的
My men will find something.
那你看到我身上有凶器吗?
Well, do you see a weapon on me?
我才不期望能在你身上看到凶器
I didn't expect to see a weapon on you.
那他们怎么不去找那个?
Well, w-why don't they look for that?
找到凶器 就找到了真正的杀手
You find that, you'll find the real killer.
或者也许他们找到了你埋凶器的地方
Or maybe they find where you planted it.
你是说我在栽赃?
So, what, I'm framing someone?
那你想过
Well, did it ever occur to you
也许有人在设计陷害我? 谁会这样做?
that someone might be framing me? Who would bother?
你知道我被关在这的原因
You know the reason I'm here.
你知道我有强大的敌人
You know I have powerful enemies.
你认为我的判断会被市长的朋友左右吗?
You think my judgment is swayed by the mayor's friends?
坐下吧
Sit your ass down.
当我13岁时
When I was 13,
我妈妈在一个有钱人家当仆人
my mother worked for a wealthy man as a maid
直到有一天
until one day
她一个人呆在房子里
she was alone in the house
和他待在一起
with him and he
所有人都知道他干了什么
Everybody knew what he did,
但是由于他是富人
but because he was rich
而我们是移民
and we were immigrants,
警察连报案都不接受
the police wouldn't even take a report.
然后 一周之后
So, a week later,
为了接近他
to gain access through his gates,
我装扮成送牛奶的——一个勒齐
I dressed as a milkman a Lechero
我确保 他得到其应有的惩罚
and I made sure that fair punishment was rendered.
现在你来说说我会怎么偏袒富人
Now you want to tell me how I favor the rich.
我知道这里的规矩 我也尊重它
I understand the rules here, and I respect them.
为什么这么急着下结论?
But why the rush to judgment?
有哪个条款规定你必须在
Is there a rule saying you must convict a suspect
10分钟内找到嫌疑犯吗
within ten minutes?
没有
No.
我们有大把时间慢慢研究
We have all the time in the world.
谢谢你
Thank you.
当然 现在我哪也不会去
Now, obviously, I'm not going anywhere.
如果你还想聊聊 我就在我的单间里
If you need to talk again, I'm gonna be in my cell.
不用了
No.
你只能坐在这把椅子上
You'll be right here in this chair.
你到底想要做什么?
What the hell do you want?
我不喜欢你
I don't like you.
当然也没有尊重你
I certainly don't respect you.
够了 你在伤害我的感觉
Stop. You're hurting my feelings.
你也知道你能干什么
I've seen at you're capable of,
但我不得不承认
but I got to say
我从来没想过你会杀人
I never pegged you as a murderer.
你认为是我杀了帝格?
You think I killed Tyge?
我今早在院子里看见你们俩了
I saw the two of you in the courtyard this morning.
我只是想跟他交朋友
I was trying to be Nice to him.
是他先和我过不去的
He started with me.
如果不是你杀的 那会是谁?
Well, if you didn't kill him, who did?
不是我
Not me.
别嘴硬了 布拉德
Come on, Brad.
除了你以为谁还会想要他的小命?
Who wanted him dead besides you?
你当真以为是我杀了那个呆瓜?
You really think I killed that frog?
我拿着枪口对着你多少次了?
How many times have I had you at gunpoint?
你以为我不想开枪?
You think I didn't want to pull that trigger?
天啊
Hell
我连自杀都没办法
I can't even kill myself.
你知道有谁看见惠斯勒从这楼梯下去吗?
Hey, you seen anyone see Whistler go down the stairway?
我们才出来1分钟
We only been out here a minute.
那么快点了
Well, hurry up, then.
惠斯勒死的越早
The sooner Whistler dies,
那我就能越早给你鸡爪
the sooner I can give you the chicken foot,
也许你更喜欢给我鸡爪
or if you prefer, you can give me the chicken foot
像个男人一样试试
you know, try and go out like a man.
随便选 你今天得和我决斗
Either way, you're getting in the ring with me today.
Zylafol 用来麻醉狗的
Zylafol. It's used to anesthetize dogs.
2滴 守卫就会在一个小时内昏迷
Two drops, and the guard should be out within an hour.
我还以为惠斯勒的女朋友会参与行动
I was expecting Whistler's girlfriend to join you.
她在哪 转角的车里?
Where is she? Around the corner in the car?
她来找过我
She came to me.
我不介意她帮助你
I don't mind that she's helping you.
我介意的是你对我保密
I mind that you kept it from me.
有什么关系呢
What difference does it make?
我是说 我们明天就散伙了 对吧?
I mean, we're done by tomorrow, right?
别再耍花样了林肯
No more surprises, Lincoln.
干吗? 说出来
What? Say it.
你能给我更多莎拉的照片吗?
Can you get any more pictures of Sara?
活着的? 当然不
Alive? No.
你没告诉他
You didn't tell him.
你没告诉迈克 莎拉已经死了
You didn't tell Michael that Sara's dead.
到底能不能弄出照片来?
Can we get pictures or not?
当然我们可以拼张出来
I'm sure we can cobble something together,
真聪明 你竟然没告诉你弟弟
but smart move not telling your brother.
他似乎对我不怎么信任
He seems a little sensitive to me.
这就是交换地点 LJ和我会那等待
This is the exchange point LJ and I will be waiting.
你迈克和惠斯勒
You, Michael and Whistler will meet us there.
一切顺利的话 你9点就能跟你儿子团聚了
Everything goes as planned, you'll have your son back by 9:00.
林肯?
Lincoln?
9点
9:00.
是哪个?
Which one is it?
不知道 我猜是高的那个
I don't know, I think it's the taller one.
-另外个一直在喝橘子汁 -你确定吗?
The other one is always drinking orange juice. You sure?
我想是的 不过不大肯定
I think so, I'm not completely sure,
他们看起来都差不多
but they all look the same. Hey
我们一直在找你
We've been trying to reach you.
索纳里面又有一具尸体
There's another dead body in Sona.
我是在
I was just
快来吧
Come on.
你要咖啡吗
You want a coffee?
给我买杯果汁吧
Get me a juice.
橘子汁
Orange juice.
请给我一杯橘子汁和一杯咖啡
One orange juice and one coffee, please.
走路看着点
Watch where you're going
这 看着
Here, look, uh
这是我伙伴的 请拿去吧
this is a buddy's, please.
不好意思 我坚持
Please, I insist.
胡塔多队长 给你重新弄了杯咖啡
Captain Hurtado Here's a new coffee.
不是的
No really.
托马 托马
Toma, Toma .
托马
Toma.
谢谢
Gracias.
伙计 我
Man, I
还是谢谢了
Thank you anyway.
不好意思 先生
Excuse me, Se?or.
我想去索纳
I need to go to Sona.
我
I
-我的车没气了 -抱歉
my car's run out of gas and Sorry.
我开的方向不对
I'm-I'm heading in the wrong, wrong direction.
我真的得到索纳去
I really need to go to Sona.
我可以载你一程
I'll give you a ride.
来吧
Come along.
谢谢你
Thank you.
小心点 别穿帮了
Watch the lid.
请接受我的哀悼
My condolences.
你终于有了个朋友 但他现在又要挂了
You finally make a friend, and now he's about to die.
真丢脸啊
Damn shame.
你可以阻止的
You can stop it, you know.
也许你还没注意到
If you hadn't noticed,
我的位置能让我获得不少事情
my position enables me to hear things.
我在听
I'm listening.
勒齐所拥有的唯一证据
The only proof Lechero's got is
就是你们下了那个楼梯 对吧
that your man went down that staircase, t?
如果你有更有说服力的证据呢?
What if you had more compelling
我没有
evidence? Well, I don't.
但如果你有呢
But if you did
你在建议我伪造点什么?
You're suggesting I make something up?
如果它能让你良心过的去的话
If it makes your conscience feel better,
然后嫁祸到某个应该得到惩罚的人的头上
then blame it on somebody who deserves it.
某个曾经杀了人
Someone who's killed before
但并未得到惩罚的凶手
and gone unpunished.
对啊 比如你
Yeah, like you maybe.
萨米
Sammy.
你想要我告诉勒齐
You want me to tell Lechero
他的左右手罪有应得?
that his right hand man should die?
你不需要要求勒齐低头
You don't tell Lechero squat.
勒齐知道
Lechero knows
这是萨米的戒指
this is Sammy's ring.
如果你把它丢到
If you drop it
楼梯上的那摊血里
in the blood by the staircase,
然后对勒齐大喊你的发现
then yell up to Lechero what you've found
那这整个
the whole entire
监狱都会听说有明确证据
prison will hear clear-cut evidence
证明萨米有罪
of Sammy's guilt.
勒齐除了遵守规定以外别无他法
Lechero will have no choice but to comply.
这就是索纳
This is Sona.
没啥好担心的
Don't worry your pretty little head about it.
你只要把戒指放进血泊中
All you have to do is drop the ring in the blood
说是萨米干的
and say it was Sammy.
剩下的就交给我
I'll take care of the rest.
想救你朋友的命么?
You want to save your friend's life?
那有人就得死
Someone else has to die.
跟帝格解释下为什么你不同意
Explain your disagreement with this Tyge man.
我听说
From what I just heard,
他知道你的一些事?
he knew something about you?
他以为他知道我的一些事
He thought he knew something about me.
时机和动机
Opportunity and a motive.
这些可不妙啊
That's not a good combination.
你也一定知道了
You must know there's discontent
大家对你的管理心存不满
from many prisoners over how you run Sona.
现在不是攻击我的时候
Now would not be a good time to insult me.
你杀了我 得到了你要的正义
you execute me, you get your swift justice
你或许可以安抚大家
and you may placate the masses.
但当他们最终发现谁做的
But when they find out who really did it
他们就会说 你杀了个无辜的人
they will know you killed an innocent man.
你还没回答我的问题
You're still not answering my question.
你和帝格到底怎么回事?
What was your disagreement with Tyge?
他是个爱管闲事的人
He was a nosy guy.
他来干涉我的事
He got into my business.
我肯定他也去管了别人的闲事
I'm sure he did the same with someone else,
所以被杀了
and that's what got him killed.
那你是承认你和他有矛盾了?
Would you just admit that you had an argument?
这里是监狱
This is prison.
如果有人对我横加指责 我当然受不了
If someone makes false accusations, I can't back down.
这点你应该清楚
You must respect that.
我已经回答了你的每个问题
Look, I've answered every one of your questions.
我已经尽全力澄清了
I've acquitted myself the best that I can.
要怎样你才相信我
Now what can I do to make you trust me?
这年头 我谁都不信
I don't trust anybody today.
一定很多人对你说过 但我还是要说
You must get this a lot, but
你真美
You're very pretty.
非常非常美
I mean very, very pretty.
怎么了?
What's the trouble?
可能你不知道 不过
You probably don't know this, but
有一种为特别的人
There is a special visitation
准备的特殊探视
for special people
我可以安排你进入索纳
I could arrange for you to go inside Sona
和你的爱人享受点二人世界
and have some private time with your love.
要想进去
And everything you would need
你所要做的
to assure your entry
都能在这辆车里完成
could be performed right here in this car.
是啊
Yeah.
照片到手了
We have the picture.
看上去怎样
How does it look?
很像莎拉
It looks like Sara.
我半小时后到索纳
I'll be at Sona in half an hour.
停车场等我
Meet me in the parking lot.
没出什么岔子吧
Is everything okay?
等下 等下 等下
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
难道你不爱你的男人?
Don't you love your man?
我不知你是否知道 但是
I don't know if you know this, but
诺曼脾气很暴躁
Norman has a terrible temper.
诺曼? 诺曼·圣约翰?
Norman? Norman St. John?
是
Si?
你是勒齐的女人?
You're one of Lechero's girls?
是
Si?
我等着呢
I'm waiting.
守卫这有点麻烦
There was a complication with the guard.
给他下药有点麻烦?
Complications drugging the guard?
是 不过还有希望
Yeah, but it's been taken care of.
好 不错
Well, that's encouraging,
你们现在下药干吗
but why are you drugging the guard
不是晚上才行动么?
now when you're escaping tonight?
要那么久才会有药物才会起效
Well, it takes that long for the drugs to work
药物1小时候就起效 我告诉过你
They take an hour, like I told you.
阿历克斯
Alex
你的表现可越来越差了 阿历克斯
You are getting sloppy,Alex.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
这是跟我开玩笑吗 -我很久以前就
Is this is a joke? I stopped hiding
不再把东西藏在床底下了
things under my mattress a long time ago.
你在我床下找到的?
Did you find that under my mattress?
如果是的话 那也是别人故意放在那里的
Cause if you did somebody put it there.
这么跟我解释可说不通
You're gonna have to do better than that.
是吗
Really?
你在刀上发现我的指纹了吗
Did you find some fingerprints on it?
啊? 还是你发现一些我的纤维了
Huh? Did you get some fibers?
你打算怎么做? 把它交给索纳的鉴证室检验一下?
What are you gonna do take it to the Sona crime lab?
他们认定是惠斯勒
They got Whistler nailed
就因为他在错误的时间去过这个楼道
for walking into the wrong stairwell.
我想凭这个
I'm thinking this is enough
就足够可以让你们俩换个处境了
to get you guys to switch places.
明白我的意思么?
You know what I mean?
什么意思? 这又能证明什么呢?
What does that mean, huh? What does that prove?
证明了一切
It proves everything
我确定勒齐也一定这么想
I'm gonna make sure Lechero thinks so, too.
迈克
Michael.
迈克我没杀他
Michael, I did not kill that man.
我没杀他
I did not kill the man.
怎么了?
What's, what's going on?
没事吧?
Is everything okay?
你想干吗?
What the hell you doing?
这是为什么?
What's that for?
你爸爸想逞英雄
Your father tried to be a hero.
不 不
No, no.
求你了 求你了
Hey, please, please.
求你了
Please.
求你了 不 停下 停下
Please, no, stop Stop
等我切断你的脊髓 再弄断几根末梢神经
Once I cut the spinal cord and the sever nerve endings,
你就什么都感觉不到了
you won't feel a thing.
不 不
No, no.
No, no
苏珊对不起
Susan, I'm sorry.
我们不是故意的
We didn't mean to do that.
爸爸 他们要杀我
Dad, they're gonna kill me.
什么 LJ?
What? LJ?
他们要割断我的喉咙
Yeah, they got a knife to my throat.
LJ
-苏珊你敢 -爸爸
Susan, don't you hurt Dad
说真话
The truth.
真话
Truth.
迈克他们3:13会出来
Michael's getting out at 3:13.
我们3:45在碰头地点会合
We're meeting at the exchange point at 3:45.
苏珊求你了 我们这么做
Susan, please, we did this
只是为了确保安全
because we wanted to make sure the site was safe.
仅此而已 这就是唯一的原因
That's it, that's the only reason why we did it.
似乎你们在耍诡计啊
Sounds to me like you're planning another end round.
再一次营救计划
Another rescue.
不 不
No, no.
不是的 我们没有
We're not, we're not planning,
没耍诡计
re not planning another end round.
不 求你 只是
No. Please, just
放我儿子一马
let my son go.
放了他
Leave my son.
活的不错?
Living the good life, huh?
不是吧
Is that what this is?
过的太滋润了
Having too good a time here
都不想离开了?
to contemplate leaving?
我需要点时间想想
I needed some time to think.
我也需要点时间
Well, I needed some time
来和巴拿马人敲定协议
to finalize our agreement with the Panamanians,
但我被人拉来了这里
but instead I get dragged down here.
是 我知道 好不容易
Yeah, I'm sure it was really hard
才说服你到这来
to convince you to come down here.
实话实说
I'm gonna be honest.
我是希望看到你这个样子
I was looking forward to seeing you
不过现在来了 我倒不这么想了
down here like this, but now i that i am here, i wouldn't wish this on anymore.
这些事能否稍后再谈
Can we just save all this till after
我不知道
I don't know if we can or not.
想好了么 阿历克斯?
Made up your mind yet, Alex?
8年 最低监禁安全级别
Eight years, minimum security.
我让他们减到4年
I got'em down to four.
今晚就去美国?
And I leave for the US tonight?
一旦
Once the special
特别检查官确认你的事
prosecutor clears you,
你就可以上路了
you'll be on your way.
特别检察官是干嘛的
What about a special prosecutor?
就是你站在人们面前
You stand in front of a guy,
告诉检察官你的经历 由他决定
you, you tell your story and he determines
当然如果你决定做证人
if you're gonna be a useful and credible witness.
那些就只是些形式了
It's a formality.
只是些形式?
"It's a formality"?
就只是形式?
This is just a formality?
小子 如果换作是我
You know, if it were up to me,
你下半辈子就等着把牢底坐穿吧
you could rot in here for the rest of your life.
但是司法部
But the Justice Department
下了很大的决心
is extremely motivated to get to the bottom
把罗纳德总统的案子一查到底
of this President Reynolds business.
阿历克斯这绝对是个好出路
Alex, this is a hundred percent above board.
你的职业生涯犯错太多
You've made a lot of mistakes in your career.
你清楚 我也清楚
You know it and I know it,
不管是不是故意的
intentional or otherwise.
我桌上已经摞了8个对你的举报
I've got eight files in my office attesting to that.
如果你不接受这些条件
And if you don't take this offer,
我敢肯定
then I assure you it would be
你一定会后悔的
the biggest mistake of your life.
我知道是谁杀的
I know who killed that man.
你当然知道了
I'm sure you do.
勒齐
Lechero
我们找到了什么
What do we have here?
我找到这个
I found this
在阿历克斯山德罗 马宏的号子里
in Alexander Mahone's cell.
你可想得真周到
Convenient
把责任都推到一个明显不再能回答问题的人身上
To blame this on a man who can't even be questioned.
够了 乔
Enough of this already. Cheo
把人都叫来
Get the prison up.
现在
this time
你知道不是惠斯勒干的
You kno Whistler didn't do this.
他说了他在马宏号子里找到匕首了啊
He just said he found the shank in Mahone's cell?
还不能证明我是清白的?
Doesn't that prove I'm innocent?
你就会扯蛋
You're a joke
你口口声声公平
You talk about equality.
公正 但归根结底
You talk justice, but at the end of the day
你不过就是一个独裁者 跟别的独裁者一样
you're a dictator, and just like any dictator
你害怕失去权力
you're terrified of losing your power.
别再考验我的耐心了 小子
It'd be very unwise to go any further.
你并不关心真正的杀人犯是谁
You don't care who the real killer is
随便抓个人就行了
just as long as you get to string somebody up.
这对你来说就完事了 对不对
That's all that matters to you, isn't it?
谁有罪 我说了算 而有罪的 都要死
I've determined who's guilty, and the punishment is death.
你错了 这是谋杀
You're making a mistake. This is murder
你清楚 我也清楚
You know it and I know it
至少你得有胆量承认
At least have the guts to admit it
没错
You're right
是谋杀
It's murder.
不要
Don't
我在院子里发现这个
I found this in the yard
这是原来奥古斯特上供给我的
Augusto used to give them to me as tribute.
现在你玷污了它
And now you reek of them.
滚吧
Go.
有什么事吗
Everything okay?
很惨吧
It's sad
走错一步 就得让个陌生人
one wrong move and a stranger
来给你下葬了
is throwing dirt on top of you.
他会没事的
He will be okay.
你怀疑你是不是真的爱自己的儿子
I question your love for your son.
他差一点就被我砍头了
He was two seconds away from being decapitated
就因为你
because of you.
我跟你说的都是实话
I told you the truth.
也许吧
Maybe.
如果你还有什么小想法
But if you have anything else planned,
趁早放弃
now it's scrapped.
因为 你知道那意味着什么
Because, what happens if you try something?
我知道
I know.
知道就好
Oh, good.
这报纸与上张照片里的是一样的
This is the same newspaper she was holding in the last picture.
我的人只能拿到这个
That's what my guy could get.
你给我的时间太有限了
You didn't give me a lot of time.
你以为迈克察觉不出?
You think Michael's not going to notice this?
那还能怎么样"迈克就就是照片"
Yeah."Hey, Michael, here's the pictures."
他会仔细看照片的
He's going to want to see this close up.
我已经帮你帮到头了
I'm done doing favors for you.
滚出去
Get out.
一小时后见
I'll see you in an hour.
今天没足球赛?
No football today?
没有
No, no football today.
我们是好兄弟吧 萨米?
You're my brother, Sammy?
那当然
Of course.
好了?
It's done?
警卫半小时内就会睡着
The guard will be asleep in a half hour.
太好了
So we're good.
还有点问题
Not quite.
他们 呃 知道了我们下午要越狱
They, uh, they know we're breaking out this afternoon.
你告诉她了?
You told her?
她猜到了
Man, she worked it out
-你撒个谎不就得了? -她猜出来了
Why didn't you lie? She worked out.
那我们现在怎么才能占到上风呢 林肯?
So what are we gonna do to get the upper hand here, Linc?
-没事 -你以为他们会给我们
Nothing. You think they're just going to turn over
-LJ和莎拉? -太冒险了
LJ and Sara? This is too dangerous.
如果我们试图救他们 他们就会
If we try anything, they're just going to
就会怎么样? 伤害他们?
What, hurt them?
不会的 只要没得到惠斯勒他们就不会乱来
No, not if they want us to deliver on Whistler, they won't.
我们直接了当点吧
We're playing this one straight.
不耍他们 不出奇兵
No games. No surprises.
行么
All right?
给我看看照片
Show me the pictures.
给我看看照片 林肯
Show me the pictures, Linc.
快点
Come on
照片
The pictures.
我不能给你看
I can't show you the pictures, man.
为什么
Why not, Linc?
她死了 迈克
She's dead, Michael.
我撒谎了
I lied to you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
如果你今天不越狱 他们会杀掉我儿子
If you don't break out today, they're going to kill my son.
他们真的会杀掉LJ
They're going to kill LJ.
迈克我们必须得干
Michael, we've got to do this.
Michael, we've got to do this
迈克
Michael
莎拉死了
Sara's dead.
他们杀了莎拉
They killed her.
真遗憾 兄弟
Oh, man, I'm so sorry.
我爱她 现在她就这么去了
I loved her and now she's gone.
全是因为你
And it's all because of you.
什么
What?
冷静点 伙计
Hey, take it easy.
什 什么?
Wh What?
全都是你的错
This is your fault.
他告诉我为什么了
He's told me his grievance.
这场决斗不可避免
This fight is going to happen.
想想你自己在干什么
Just think about what you're doing.
我想过了
I have.